The fairytale is over
Snow White and the Huntsman is a adventure, fantasy,
drama film directed by Rupert Sanders.
After the Evil Queen marries the King, she performs a violent coup in which the
King is murdered and his daughter, Snow White, is taken captive.
Almost a decade later, a grown Snow White is still in the clutches of the Queen.
In order to obtain immortality, The Evil Queen needs the heart of Snow White.
After Snow escapes the castle, the Queen sends the
Huntsman to find her in the Dark Forest.
Snow White, played by Kristen Stewart.
The Huntsman, played by Chris Hemsworth.
Queen Ravenna, played by Charlize Theron.
William, played by Sam Claflin.
Beith, played by Ian McShane.
Gort, played by Ray Winstone.
Snow White & the Huntsman is a 2012 American dark fantasy action-adventure film directed by
Rupert Sanders and written by Evan Daugherty, John Lee Hancock, and Hossein Amini.
Produced by Roth Films and distributed by Universal Pictures, the film is based on the Brothers Grimm's 1812 fairy
tale "Snow White," and stars Kristen Stewart, Charlize Theron, Chris Hemsworth, and Sam Claflin.
The plot follows princess Snow White, who grows up imprisoned by
her evil stepmother, the powerful sorceress Ravenna.
After Snow White escapes into the forest, Ravenna enlists a huntsman named Eric to capture her, but he
eventually becomes Snow White's companion in a quest to overthrow Ravenna and end her dark reign.
Snow White & the Huntsman was theatrically released in the United Kingdom on May 30,
2012, and in the United States on June 1, 2012, by Universal Pictures.
The film was a box office success, having grossed $396.6
million worldwide against a $170 million budget.
Critics praised the production design and visual effects, and Theron's and Hemsworth's performances, as well as James Newton
Howard's score, while the action sequences and Stewart's and Claflin's performances received mixed reviews.
The film received two Oscar nominations for Best Visual Effects and Best Costume Design at the
85th Academy Awards; Stewart won Worst Actress at the 33rd Golden Raspberry Awards.
A sequel, titled The Huntsman: Winter's War, directed by the first film's visual effects supervisor Cedric
Nicolas-Troyan, was released on April 22, 2016, with Hemsworth, Theron, Claflin, and Nick Frost reprising their roles.
The film explores themes of magic, immortality, fairy tale, queen, imprisonment.
The tone is dark and emotional.